[
    {
        "question": "Which country lies between Switzerland and Austria?",
        "answer": "Liechtenstein"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bridgetown is the capital of which Caribbean island?",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the warm dry wind which blows over the Rocky Mountains?",
        "answer": "The Chinook"
    },
    {
        "question": "The island of Madeira belongs to which European country?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many provinces are there in Canada?",
        "answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which US coast can Redwood trees be found?",
        "answer": "West coast"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is located on the northern border of Pennsylvania?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What fruit is grown extensively on Cape Cod?",
        "answer": "Cranberries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Utah?",
        "answer": "Salt Lake City"
    },
    {
        "question": "Berlin stands on the banks of which river?",
        "answer": "Spree"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is America`s oldest continually operating drive-in theater?",
        "answer": "Orefield, Pennsylvania -- Opened in 1934, Shankweiler`s Drive-In Theatre is an American institution."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is typically considered the largest island in the world?",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capita of Greenland?",
        "answer": "Nuuk"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nuuk is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which islands were the subject of a war between Argentina and United Kingdom in the 1980s?",
        "answer": "Falklands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Switzerland and what other country both have square flags?",
        "answer": "Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the centuries-old Maiden Tower?",
        "answer": "Baku, Azerbaijan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city`s buildings include the John Hancock Center and the Amoco Building?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Cleveland is located on the shores of which Great Lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Erie"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Craters of the Moon National Monument?",
        "answer": "Idaho"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Wisconsin?",
        "answer": "Madison"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Griffith Park?",
        "answer": "Los Angeles"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?",
        "answer": "Moscow"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Centennial Olympic Park?",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Tivoli Gardens?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Grant Park?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find `Muscle Beach` in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Venice Beach, California -- Muscle Beach attracts bodybuilders from all over with its unique outdoor weight room on the beach."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. city will you find Vieux Carr\u00e9 neighborhood?",
        "answer": "New Orleans, Louisiana -- Known to most tourists as the French Quarter, the term means `Old Square.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mt. Elbrus, the tallest peak in Europe, is located where?",
        "answer": "Russia -- The native Balkars call it `Mingi-Tau`, which means `resembling a thousand mountains,` due to its sheer size."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Richard Nixon Presidential Library is located in which California city?",
        "answer": "Yorba Linda"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became Romanian President after the 1989 Revolution?",
        "answer": "Ion Iliescu"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which two European countries can you hear residents speaking Basque?",
        "answer": "France and Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Smithsonian Institution is located in which city?",
        "answer": "Washington D.C."
    },
    {
        "question": "The `Sherwood Forest Plantation`, home to U.S. President John Tyler, is located in which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which river does Washington D.C. stand?",
        "answer": "The Potomac"
    },
    {
        "question": "Into which bay does the Ganges flow?",
        "answer": "The Bay of Bengal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest mountain in Wales?",
        "answer": "Mount Snowdon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did Bangladesh declare its independence from Pakistan?",
        "answer": "1971"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bangladesh is located at the apex of which Bay?",
        "answer": "Bay of Bengal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What land feature separates Bangladesh from Nepal and Bhutan?",
        "answer": "Siliguri Corridor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two countries share land borders with Bangladesh?",
        "answer": "India and Myanmar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean does Bangladesh have direct access to?",
        "answer": "Indian Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Cuba?",
        "answer": "Havana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Havana is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    },
    {
        "question": "St. Louis` Gateway Arch is officially named for what US president?",
        "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state depicts Delicate Arch on its license plates?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which non-coastal western US state has the seagull as its official state bird?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian provinces are known as the `Maritime Provinces`?",
        "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What`s the largest country entirely within the southern hemisphere?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    }
]